William Temple Franklin Papers 1775-1819 Mss.B.F86
American Philosophical Society
- William Temple Franklin Papers, 1775-1790; Mss.B.F86; 4.5 lin. feet
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 July 12; ALS, 1p.; Feutry, Aimé Ambroise Joseph
    Thanking him for the Madeira he sent him during his convalescence.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 July 17; ALS, 3p.; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808
    Sends her letter by Mrs. McCarty whom his grandfather was well acquainted with in Canada. Mrs. [Dorcas] Montgomery is going in the same vessel, but she is not on good terms with her now. Old Dr. [William] Shippen has just called with a letter for Dr. Franklin; tells a wonderful story about his son's house being struck by lightning. Mr. Bryson is still in the postoffice.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 July 19; ALS, 2p.; MacCreery, William
    Is on board the Continental brig "Active," which came from Nantes to sail with the convoy bound for the West Indies. Three warships and a cutter are with the convoy. A signal has just been put out for the fleet to get ready to sail.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 July 21; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Introducing Samuel Griffitts who is going to Europe to prosecute his studies.
  - to William Temple Franklin., [ca.1781] July 21; ALS, 1p.; Corsange, -----
    Has only been able to obtain the book this morning, sends it by a messenger. Mr. [Ferdinand] Grand wants to know the fate of Messers Parish and Thomson's bills.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 July 22; ALS, 1p.; Mayo, Joseph
    Encloses bill of exchange drawn on Le Ray de Chaumont for 1,500 livres. Has received 949 livres on account.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 July 24; ALS, 1p.; Feutry, Aimé Ambroise Joseph
    His trip yesterday and kind reception by Dr. Franklin and his grandson have considerably hastened his return to health.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 July 24; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Is ready to pay what [Jonathan Loring?] Austin owes Dr. Franklin. Inquires if any new orders for clothing are to be given by Congress, to replace those lost on the "Marquis Lafayette."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 July 25; ALS, 4p.; de La Salle, Comtesse
    Recommending a young man who seeks to be employed by him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 July 26; ALS, 3p.; Alexander, Alexander John
    Has just arrived at his destination after a very long voyage from Paris. Heard reports in the English islands about battles in which the Americans were defeated; does not credit such reports.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 July 26; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Request to buy him some paper and send recipe for making ink.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 July 28; ALS, 2p.; Fox, George
    Has decided to start for Holland soon after he arrives at Paris. Refers to [Joseph] Mayo and [John] Foulke.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 7; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Sends a package of bills for acceptance. Capt. [John] Folger, who visited Passy recently, regarded in America as a Tory. Refers to rumors of approaching peace and begs to be given a hint in time. Has received letters from Aunt [Jane] Mecom and Mr. [Richard] Bache.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 9; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Will be glad to see Mr. Young if he comes to Nantes and will do all he can for him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 13; ALS, 1p.; Warren, Winslow
    Requests him to ask M. [Ferdinand] Grand to advance him 100 pounds; will repay as soon as he receives a letter from
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 14; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Returning Capt. Collyer's bond and enclosing bills on the Commissioners.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 18; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Requesting a passport for Joseph HIll Jennings, who is going from Nantes into Spain.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 18; ALS, 2p. Enclosure. 3p.; Hartley, Samuel
    Sends copies of two letters received from a house at Cape San Domingo relating to the circumstances of the seizure of the ship "Diamond" with cargo of slaves and dry goods. Claims the seizure was illegal and has entered a protest at Paris against it.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 20; ALS, 2p.; Carmichael, William, d. 1795
    Is translating enclosures contained in his letter into Spanish. Occupies a pavillion of the house in which the Prince of Masseran lived last year; is pleased to hear of the Princess's remembrance of him. Is on a friendly footing with all the foreign Secretaries. Knew Mr. [John] Adams's visit to Paris was on account of the proposed conferences for peace; is not surprised at his silence towards Dr. Franklin. Deplores the jealousy displayed by the American envoys towards each other and their lack of cooperation. If Comte de Grasse has a favorable passage, a blow may be struck at the headquarters of toryism in America. No news of the Duke de Crillon's arrival at Minorca. Desires a seal ring to be purchased for him with the head of Brutus, Socrates or Dr. Franklin on it.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 28; ALS, 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Learns that the clothing and arms for the army are to be furnished by the (French) Government; does not except any part in it. Twice contributed 50 guineas anonymously to Mrs. Johnson's support after the Barbadoes calamity; shall take care that she does not suffer, but does not wish to be known in the matter.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Aug. 29; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Perregaux, -----
    Sends a letter received from Mr. [Samuel] Hartley.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 1; ALS, 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Encloses a letter to M. [Jean François Joly] de Fleury; if endorsed by Dr. Franklin, thinks it will procure him part of the new order for supplies.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [ca.1781] Sept. 3; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Warren, Winslow
    Requests return of bills left in his care.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 4; L.S. 2p.; Holker, M. John Jr
    Can only correspond with Le Ray de Chaumont about the matters in question. Tells of Mr. [Richard] Bache being nearly killed by a thrust from a cow's horn.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 4; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Mason, George Jr.
    Request for a letter which Capt. [William] Robeson left with Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 11; ALS, 2p.; Robeson, William
    Is surprised at the arrival and request of W. Montague, the young African. Intends, as promised, to set him up as a barber in America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 12; L.S. 3p.; "Freedom." Dublin
    Hopes he has received a letter from his partner and nephew who sailed in the brig "Lord Charlemont." Proposes sending another vessel soon to America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 12; ALS, 2p.; Mason, George Jr.
    Requests that a passport be procured for him from Comte de Vergennes, to go to the South of France.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 12; A.L.S 1p.; Mayo, Joseph. Passy
    Incloses letters to be forwarded to America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 14; N. in 3d P. 1p.; d'Estaing, Comte
    Inquires how much an acre of ground in North America is equivalent to in French measurements.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 15; ALS, 2p.; Robeson, Capt. William
    With reference to young Montague, his colored servant.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 17; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Johonnot,Gabriel
    Is leaving for Orleans and his son [Samuel Cooper Johonnot] for Geneva. Requests a few lines of introduction to Mr. [Jonathan] Williams, [Jr.], and other merchants of
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Sept. 21; ALS, 2p.; Carmichael, William, d. 1795
    Introduces Major [David Salisbury] Franks and requests that he be shown particular attention; is well and favorably known throughout the Union and could counteract the work of their common personal enemies at home. Refers to A[rthur] L[ee] as one of the bitterest and alludes to his ambition to become Secretary of Foreign Affairs. Dr. Franklin has now the same commission as Mr. [John] Adams.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 1; ALS, 2p.; Vaughan, John
    Introducing Major David [Salisbury] Franks whose mission to Europe is known to him. Saw a lightning conductor upon a powder magazine at Segovia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 1; ALS, 3p.; Foulke, John, 1757-1796
    Gives an account of his journey through Holland and part of Germany. Is racked and fatigued after a long and arduous journey.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [ca.1781] Oct. 1; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Warren, Winslow
    Is about to set out for Nantes; offers to take any letters or messages for that place.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 3; ALS, 1p.; Ross, John
    Latest events of the war. [Gen.Lord] Cornwallis besieged at Yorktown by land and sea; the English fleet returned to New York badly battered; report of a bloody battle in South Carolina between Gen. [Nathanael] Greene's army and the British.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 3; ALS, 2p.; Ingersoll, Jared
    Introducing Mr. Hopkins and Mr. Gibbs, who are going to France. Gives an account of a battle in South Carolina between Gen. Greene and the English troops.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 3; A.N. in 3d P. 2p.; Jay, Mrs. John
    Requesting him to purchase and send her by Major [David Salisbury] Franks, two pairs of paste shoe buckles, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 4; ALS, 2p.; Bache, Richard
    Replies to inquiry about Philip Dieffenbach and the Mengs family. Will forward seeds as soon as Mr. [William] Bartram puts them up. Request civilities for Capt. Hoops a American officer and a brother of Mrs. [Thomas] Barclay, who was taken prisoner at the battle of Camden and is going to Europe on a furlough.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 5; ALS, 1p.; Bache, Richard
    Introducing Capt. Hoops, brother-in-law of Mr. [Thomas] Barclay recently appointed Consul General to France, who is going to France with his sister.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 6; ALS, 1p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de, fils
    Preparing a celebration for his mother's feast day. Would like to get some verses from M. [Amé Ambroise Joseph] Feutry for the occasion. Invities William Temple Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 8; A.L.S 1p.; Schaffer, John
    Relating to endorsement of his bills by Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 10; ALS, 1p.; Lloyd, Richard Bennett. Annapolis, Md
    Have had many festivities in honor of the French troops. Considers them a fine body of men.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 11; ALS, 1p.; Johonnot,Gabriel
    Expressing thanks to Abbé Arnoux and his friend M. Jaume, of Lyons, for their attentions to his son [Samuel Cooper Johonnot].
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 15; ALS, 2p.; Woolford, Mrs. D.
    Acknowledging the receipt of Dr. Franklin's bounty to Mrs. Johnson. Delivered book and letter to Mr. Small. References to Mrs. Thackwell and Miss Marcey.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 16; ALS, 1p.; Warren, Winslow. Ancenis
    Relating to the repayment of 25 guineas loaned to him by Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 18; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Accepts Dr. Franklin's approval of his application to M. [Jean François Joly] de Fleury to furnish supplies. Has no funds belonging to Capt. [William] R[obeson] who is considerably in his debt.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Oct. 20; A.L.S 1p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de
    Requests him to call at the office of the "Gazette de France" and get several copies of the paper containing an account of the victory over [Gen. Lord] Cornwallis, which Dr. Franklin wishes to send to Madrid.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Oct. 31; ALS, 3p.; Richard Neave and Son. Bornier
    Are greatly disappointed at not being able to obtain advances of money, as they have considerable property in America. Are in a very unpleasant situation owing to Mr. [Samuel] Wharton's ingratitude. Enclose a letter for Mr. Carson, their attorney at Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 8; ALS, 2p.; Robeson, Capt. William
    Promises to remit money due him and Mr. Raymond.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 9; ALS, 2p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Encloses a letter from his brother, which he wishes to have certified by Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 10; ALS, 1p.; Fox, George. Valenciennes
    Have had to stop on their journey to Brussels, owing to excessive fatigue. Have not been in bed since they left Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 14; ALS, 2p.; Mayo, Joseph. Brussels
    Reached Brussels last night in company with [George] Fox; Fox has set out for Amsterdam. Expects to receive letters and bills of exchange from America soon.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 14; ALS, 1p. (Enclosure. 2p.); Alexander, William
    Encloses a letter for Abbé de la Roche and one from Capt. [John] Kinnier, an Engliish prisoner at Ancenis, who begs to be exchanged with his crew for American prisoners in England. Capt. [Gustavus] Cun[n]ingham has had an offer of a 30-gun French frigate, but will not accept without an American commission.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 15; ALS, 3p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de, fils
    Gives an account of their hunting expeditions. Request to buy him several articles in Paris.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 16; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Requesting that the copy of Dr. Franklin's letter to his brother be returned to him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 16; ALS, 1p.; de Soubise, Maréchal Prince
    Sending him two game licenses.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 17; ALS, 3p.; Franks, Major David Salisbury
    May have to wait several months before he can get passage on a vessel for America. Hears that part of the fleet at Brest will sail for America; asks if he may go to Brest to await orders. Refers to the de Chaumont and Mme. de Deux-Ponts families.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 18; ALS, 2p.; Fox, George
    Tells of his arrival and of delivering despatches to Mr. [John] Adams. His first impression of the people of Holland, the climate, etc., most unfavorable. Refers to [Joseph] Mayo, [John] Foulke, and [George] Harrison.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 19; ALS, 1p.; Knox, William. On board "L'Engageant," Road of Groia
    Encloses a letter with request that it be forwarded to destination.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 20; L.S. 3p.; Shee, John
    Sends a copy of the letter written to Silas Deane with reference to the sale of his Loan Office certificates. Requests return of his power of attorney given to Silas Deane.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 21; ALS, 1p.; Franks, Major David Salisbury
    Introducing Mr. Hoops, a young American officer who is a prisoner to the English but who is on furlough.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 23; ALS, 1p.; Warren, Winslow. Ancenis
    Encloses letter from a Scotch Captain, a prisoner of war, about his exchange. Promises to repay Dr. Franklin the 25 louis he owes him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Nov. 24; ALS, 2p.; Bache, Richard
    Request to interest himself in Mr. [John] Shee's affair. Has procured the seeds from Mr. [William] Bartram and has shipped two boxes of them on the brig "Bets[e]y."
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Nov. 25; ALS, 2p.; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789
    Sends copy of a letter from Capt. [John] Cochran, of Philadelphia, relating to payment of his son's tuition in a school at Paris.
    Bibliography
    Printed in Collections of New York Historical Society, 1889. Deane Papers, IV, 541.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Nov. 25; ALS, 1p.; Andrews, Samuel
    Sends invitation from Mme. Droin; M. Grand to be of the party.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Nov. 26; ALS, 3p.; Fox, George
    Fears he may become stupid owing to the depressing effect of the climate. [Joseph] Mayo finds Brussels more agreeable. Has not yet presented his letter of introduction to M. Grand de La Chaise. Remarks on Cornwallis's surrender.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Nov. 30; ALS, 2p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de, fils
    Request to purchase three kegs of powder for him at the Arsenal. Tells of another accident in which he was nearly killed.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Nov. 30; ALS, 2p.; Bache, Richard
    Relating to shipment of boxes of seeds and pippin grafts; cannot procure squirrel skins. Asks his opinion as to the effect of Cornwallis's surrender.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Dec. 1; ALS, 3p.; Mayo, Joseph. Brussels
    Thanks for the copy of Count de Vergennes's letter narrating the surrender of Cornwallis. Tells of a person having lately seen and conversed with Mr. [Henry] Laurens in the Tower of London; implies he has been treated with severity and rigor. [George] Fox's opinion of the Dutchmen's hospitality. Likes Brussels but finds the climate too damp.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1781 Dec. 3; ALS, 4p.; Ross, John
    Improved conditions in the country in general. The assistance of France very valuable to the United States. The lack of economy and squandering of the public funds caused much want and distress in the beginning. The Marquis Lafayette has set out for Boston to embark for France. Silas Deane's recently published letter has caused surprise and resentment against him; his strictures on the vanity and folly of some Americans in Europe very often justified.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 3.; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Le Couteulx and Cie
    Returning draft for £2,000 accepted by them.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 5; ALS, 3p.; Jay, John
    The arrival of Mr. [Thomas] Barclay will relive Dr. Franklin from much trouble. Rejoicings over the birth of the Dauphin and the success of the allied armies in America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 5; ALS, 2p.; Fox, George
    Great rejoicing amongst the Americans on receipt of news telling of the surrender of Cornwallis. Thinks if Charlestown and New York were retaken it would end the war. Inquires if the "St. James", from Philadelphia, brings news of any material changes in that city.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 6; A.N.; Chaumont, Le Ray de, fils
    Expressing his thanks for Mme. H ----'s letter forwarded to him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 10; ALS, 3p.; Franks, Major David Salisbury
    Fears that his prolonged stay, waiting for a vessel, will be very expensive to the Government at home. The number of people arrived with the Franch fleets of war have caused a scarcity of necessaries of life; prices are very high. The "St. James," Capt. [Thomas] Truxton, probably the first vessel which will sail for America about Jan. 15. His situation very unpleasant and embarrassing. Was arrested the other day on suspicion of being a spy.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 13.; ALS, 3p.; Vaughan, John
    Was obliged to leave Madrid and come to Cadiz on account of his health. Intends soon to embark for America; will make his head-quarters at Philadelphia. Comments on Cornwallis's surrender and its effect on England.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 13; ALS, 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Refers to Major [David Salisbury] Franks and to M. Montfort whom Silas Deane has urged him to employ in his counting house. Asks what are Thomas Barclay's intentions regarding Consuls in different ports. Requests to be kept posted on the trend to events, as it is a critical time for American trade. Encloses letter from M. [Andrew] Limozin of Havre.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 15; A.L. 1p.; Grand, Henry
    Relating to payment of Loan Office certificates.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 15; ALS, 2p.; Babut and La bouchère
    Do not know anything about the 400 pounds of indigo referred to by Mr. Cochran, as having passed through Col. [John] Laurens's hands. The latter alone can clear up the matter.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 19; ALS, 2p.; Thaxter, John
    Introducing Dr. Dexter who is going to Paris with Thomas and Joseph Winthrop and Dr. Parker. Has forwarded the Journal of Congress for 1778 to Dr. Franklin. Refers to Mr. [George] Fox as a very worthy character.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 21; ALS, 1p.; Angenend, -----
    Sends samples of velvet for Dr. Franklin's costume.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 22; A.L.S 3p.; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789
    Refers to young Cochran's embarrassing situation. Is surprised that Mr. [Thomas] Barclay has no orders from Congress for settling its public accounts in Europe.
    Printed in Collection of New York Historical Society, 1889, Deane Papers, IV, 554.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 23; ALS, 3p.; Franks, Major David Salisbury
    With great difficulty, got a pass for Capt. Smedley to go to l'Orient to embark in the " St. James." Complains that the authorities at Brest are not friendly towards Americans; has been treated with suspicion. Inquires about Count William de Deux-Ponts; mentions "the lovely Countess and Lady Nicholson.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 23; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Gives the address of Bertrand from whom he bought his sword and recomends him as an honest man.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Dec. 26; ALS, 4p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Refers to reply to M. [Andrew] Limozin's application for Consulate at Havre. Speaks of the Captain's [William Robeson] indebtedness to them both. Is about to send two fine Cheshire cheeses and a few boxes of tea for Dr. Franklin and Abbé Morellet. Has bought some fine old Madeira wine recently and will send half a pipe to the Doctor.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Labhard, Mademoiselle
    Wishes to know where she can get the benches like those used for his fête.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [ca.1781] April 1; ALS, 1p.; de Bonne, Souer
    Will lend him his riding horse.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1779 May; ALS, 3p.; Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Leray de, 1725-1803
    The vessel is ready to start; the medallion of Dr. Franklin is on board, he hopes the English will not capture it; since he last wrote he made a little trip to Dinan, St. Malo, etc.; at Cancale he saw the two frigates burnt. The country is in a sad state, with its commerce ruined.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781 Jan-March; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Dana, Francis M
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; ALS, 2p.; Deux-Ponts, Marianne Camasse, duchesse La douairière de
    Is alarmed at reports about Dr. Franklin's health. Sends a package to be forwarded to her son [Guillaume Comte de Deux-Ponts] in America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1781.; L. 1p.; Foulke, Dr. John
    Thanks him for his inquiries about his health; will call on him soon.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; ALS, 1p.; Foulke, Dr. John
    Asks that the passports from the Comte de Vergennes be given to the bearer.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Foulke, Dr. John
    Thanks him for procuring the apartment in Paris; Captain [William] Robeson's letter will receive great care; accepts the invitation for dinner.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; ALS, 2p.; Franks, David
    Having recovered from his illness, he will take possession of the room he offers.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; A.N.S. 2p.; Franks, David
    Sends his servant to Dr. Franklin's house for some clothing he left there.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1781.; ALS, 1p.; Grand, Henry